Elia Bellussi, MBA

Orbassano, Torino ITALY | +39 3336892117 | +44 7775701751

e.bellussi@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/eliabellussi/ | https://github.com/ebellussi

ROFESSIONAL SUMMARY __

Innovation manager with 10+ years of experience working in relationship management, system engineering, and project management with stakeholders and clients such as the public sector, aerospace, telecommunication, and banking. Specialized in emerging technology, digital transformation, strategy and business development, and open innovation. Excellent organizational, communication, and presentation skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ALMAVIVA — Turin, Italy

June 2020 – Present

Innovation Manager

- Providing intellectual and methodological leadership in projects and proposals, coordinating teams in European calls for tenders, focusing on excellence and impact.
- Contributing to the leadership and growth of the company by bringing fresh and innovative ideas, designing innovation processes, methodologies, and strategies, implementing networks of partners and experts whom the company will be able to activate from day one to manage and deliver diverse projects as well as start-ups' scouting and evaluation.
- Introducing ideation of customised solutions for public administrations and the national healthcare system, leading their digital transformation with a focus on artificial intelligence, especially about ethics, the internet of things, and blockchain.

SAA – SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT — Turin, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

Teacher Assistant

- Overseeing case studies analysis for the course in Management Information Systems and Internal Control.
- Guiding lectures with practical examples from businesses to clarify how companies manage different issues in their business-related arguments of the course.

CONSOFT SISTEMI — Turin, Italy

May 2011 – June 2020

Corporate Business Solutions Manager

- Headed the Big Data practice of the company, creating a cross-functional team and developing the business plan.
- Provided courses on NoSQL with a particular focus on MongoDB for bTicino, a subsidiary of Legrand group.
- Trained and tutored a colleague for a project on Big Data Analytics with a Hadoop infrastructure.

Senior System Engineer

- Coordinated projects on continual service development through process design and analytics with a particular focus on KPIs and quality management for GE Avio Aero and Skylogic, a subsidiary of Eutelsat.
- Managed a tailored monitoring system related to the effectiveness of the company's infrastructure of 7.000 servers for Intesa Sanpaolo, as a product owner in an agile team.
- Contributed to the development and management of different projects/B2B products, in collaboration between the enterprise service desk and the enterprise projects development team for GE Avio Aero.

COMAU — Rivalta di Turin, Italy

Feb 2017 – Feb 2017

Guest Lecturer

- Conducted lectures for an Executive Master of Digital Innovation, collaborating with ESCP Business School (Birmingham, UK).
- Trained and motivated a group of 30 executive students on coding and its impact on digital transformation.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

CLUB DIRIGENTI INFORMATICI — Turin, Italy

March 2021 – Present

Board of Directors

- Orchestrating events organisation from managing associated resources to executing the strategies.
- Operating guests, sponsors, and partners research, providing analysis and recommendations.
- Exploring new partners and interacting with them to create a solid network of stakeholders.

SOCIAL INNOVATION TEAM — Turin, Italy

March 2021 - Present

Startup Mentor

- Reorganising, redesigning, and strengthening the business strategy, product development, and financial statements.
- Coaching start-ups' teams to understand customers' needs and wants and to apply design thinking methodology.

IMPACT HUB — Milan, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

Startup Mentor

Mentoring and training teams on design thinking, helping them to develop their business model and strategies.

STARTUP GEEKS — Milan, Italy

Nov 2020 – Present

Startup Mentor

• Supervising teams following the program, providing support and information to be able to complete the assignments.

DIGITAL360 — Milan, Italy

Feb 2020 – Present

Contributing Writer

• Authoring articles on Design Thinking, Data Strategy, Scenario Planning published in Italian online magazines.

EDUCATION_

Master of Science in Artificial Intelligence (MSc)

Expected 2022

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy

Natural Language Processing – Computer Vision – Multi-Agents System – AI Ethics.

Master of Science in Disruptive Innovation (MDI)

Mar 2020

HULT International Business School — San Francisco, USA – GPA: 3.61 with Distinction

Design Thinking – System Thinking – Scenario Planning – Leading Digital Innovation – Co-Creation – Open Innovation.

Master of Business Administration (MBA)

Aug 2019

HULT International Business School — London, UK – GPA: 3.26

Major in Project Management – Minor in Marketing & Sales – Campuses: London, Dubai, and Shanghai.

Bachelor of Computer Science (BSc)

Oct 2011

Università Degli Studi di Turin — Turin, Italy Artificial Intelligence and Multi-Agent System.

Languages

Italian (Native); English (Advanced); Spanish (Basic).

SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS _

Work Authorization: EU citizen.

Languages: Italian (native), English (fluent), Spanish (elementary).

Certifications: ITIL V3 Foundation, Foundations in Design Thinking (IDEO), Professional Scrum Master I (Scrum.org).

Memberships: IEEE (https://www.ieee.org). Club Dirigenti Informatici (http://www.clubdi.org/). AICA

(http://www.aica.it/)

VIGICII ZOZI - TTCSCII